<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="search" full_name="Simple Search">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
Simple Search is a simple search engine that performs a quick search of
a website and displays links to files containing the text search for.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>search.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The Simple Search Perl script.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file.  Instructions on how to configure and install</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>Simple Search.</filename>
       <filedesc></filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>search.html</filename>
       <filedesc>A sample HTML file demonstrating how to use Simple Search.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFEST</filename>
       <filedesc>List of files included with the Simple Search distribution.</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you can change in search.pl which
alter the way that the program works.  $basedir and $baseurl are the two
most important variables, and must be altered to refer to your website.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
Simple Search is installed simply by copying the file search.pl into
your cgi-bin directory.  If you don't know the location of your cgi-bin
directory, then please ask your system administrator.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Depending on how the HTTP server is configured, you may need to rename
search.pl to search.cgi.  Again, your system administrator will know if
this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file
search.pl.  If you have shell access to the HTTP server, you can do this
by running the command `chmod +x search.pl` from the command line.
If you don't have command line access then there will probably be an
equivalent function (to change file mode) in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Simple Search will scan and search all directories and subdirectories
from a start point (defined by $basedir).  There are 4 different
parameters that can be passed to it:  case, bool, and terms.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    case
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
        This parameter defines whether a search will be case-sensitive or
        case-insensitive.  The default is case-insensitive.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    bool
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
        If there is more then one term in the search query, this parameter
        defines whether the terms AND'ed or OR'ed.  The default is OR.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    terms
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
        This parameter contains the terms that will be searched.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    directory
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
        This optional parameter will only be used if $emulate_matts_code
        is set to 0.  It is the zero based index into the configuration
        variable @subdirs which allows you to specify an alternate
        starting subdirectory for your search: this might be useful if
        you have the content on your site arranged in categories by
        directory.  You will probably want to use a drop-down list so
        that users of Simple Search don't need to know the numbers.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
See the search.html file bundled with the Simple Search distriubtion for
an example of how to fully construct a form to use with simple search.
As an example, a small form can be embedded into a page using a construct
similar to the following:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    <form method="post" action="/cgi-bin/search.pl">
        <input type="text" name="terms" size="40" />
        <input type="submit" />
    </form>
</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
