<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="textclock" full_name="Text Clock">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
textclock displays the current time on a web page. It is intended to be used
as a Server Side Include program.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>textclock.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The main perl script.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file. Instructions on how to install and use textclock.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFESTO</filename>
       <filedesc>List of files</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you can change in textclock.pl which
alter the way that the program works.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$DEBUGGING</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be set to 1 whilst you are installing
                and testing the script. Once the script is live you
                should change it to 0. When set to 1, errors will
                be output to the browser. This is a security risk and
                should not be used when the script is live.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$Display_Time_Zone</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            Each of these variables controls the display of the relevant
                part of the date or time. If the variable is set to 1, then
                that part of the date/time is displayed. If it is set to 0
                then that part of the date/time is omitted.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
textclock is installed simply by copying the file textclock.pl.pl into your
cgi-bin directory. If you don't know where your cgi-bin directory is, then
please ask your system administrator
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You may need to rename textclock.pl to textclock.cgi. Again, your system
administrator will know if this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file. You can
do this by running the command "chmod +x textclock.pl" from your command
line. If you don't have command line access to your web server then there
will probably be an equivalent function in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Then, edit your HTML files and wherever you want to display the time, insert
the following:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
     <!--#exec cgi="/cgi-bin/textclock.pl"-->
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Note: As this is a "Server Side Include" you will need to ensure that your
web server has been configured to support SSI. Also, it's possible that you
may need to rename any files that include SSI calls to give them a different
extension. A common choice is .shtml. Your system administrator will be able
to help you with these details.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>


</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
