<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="rand_image" full_name="">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
rand_image chooses a random image from a set of predefined images and
displays it on a webpage.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>rand_image.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The main perl script.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file. Instructions on how to install and use rand_image.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFESTO</filename>
       <filedesc>List of files</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you can change in rand_image.pl which
alter the way that the program works.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$DEBUGGING</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be set to 1 whilst you are installing
                and testing the script. Once the script is live you
                should change it to 0. When set to 1, errors will
                be output to the browser. This is a security risk and
                should not be used when the script is live.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$basedir</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The URL of the directory where your images are located. For
                example:
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>@files</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The lsit of image files that the random image is chosen from.
                These filenames will be appended to the
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$uselog</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            Set this value to 1 to log which image is returned each time
                the program runs.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$logfile</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The path to the logfile, only needed if
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
rand_image is installed simply by copying the file rand_image.pl into your
cgi-bin directory. If you don't know where your cgi-bin directory is, then
please ask your system administrator
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You may need to rename rand_image.pl to rand_image.cgi. Again, your system
administrator will know if this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file. You can
do this by running the command "chmod +x rand_image.pl" from your command
line. If you don't have command line access to your web server then there
will probably be an equivalent function in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Then, edit your HTML files and change all the images that you want to
be randomized to:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
<img src="http://your.host.com/cgi-bin/rand_image.pl" />
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
This is just an example, so be sure to insert the correct URL of your
rand_image.pl installation.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>


</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
