<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="imagecounter" full_name="Image Counter">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
Image Counter allows you to have a counter on your web site using graphical
images as the digits.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>icounter.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The main program file</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>digits/*.gif</filename>
       <filedesc>The sample image files in GIF format</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>digits/*.png</filename>
       <filedesc>The sample image files in PNG format</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFEST</filename>
       <filedesc>A list of all the files</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you may want to change in icounter.pl
which alter the way the program works.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$DEBUGGING</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be set 1 whist you are installing and 
                testing your Image Counter as iit controls whether error
                messages the program might generate are sent to the
                client browser.  After you have finished testing and
                everything is fine then you should set it to 0.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$data_dir</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This is the path to the directory where the counter files
                will be stored.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$digit_url</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be the beginning of the URL for the location
                where your digit images are.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$digit_ext</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The file extension of the digit files - the default '.gif'
                is correct for supplied sample digits but if you create
                your own digits with a different extension (e.g. '.png')
                then you will have to change this as appropriate.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>@invalid_uri</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            Together these two variables control which URIs on your
                server are allowed to use this program to monitor their hits.

                The rule is that a URI can use this program if it matches one
                of the expressions in
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$auto_create</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            If this variable is true (i.e. 1) then any counters that are
                not found will be automatically created. If it is false (i.e.
                0) any counters that are not found will trigger an error.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$ssi_emit_cgi_headers</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should normally be set to 1.  You may need to
                        change this to 0 if you are seeing stuff output
                        that you didn't expect as described below.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
Image Counter is installed simply by copying the file icounter.pl into your
cgi-bin directory. If you don't know where your cgi-bin directory is, then
please ask your system administrator.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You may need to rename icounter.pl to icounter.cgi. Again, your system
administrator will know if this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file. You can
do this by running the command "chmod +x icounter.pl" from your command
line. If you don't have command line access to your web server then there
will probably be an equivalent function in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Then, edit your HTML files and wherever you want to display the counter,
insert the following:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
     <!--#exec cgi="/cgi-bin/icounter.pl"-->
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Note: As this is a "Server Side Include" you will need to ensure that
your web server has been configured to support SSI. Also, it's possible
that you may need to rename any files that include SSI calls to give them
a different extension. A common choice is .shtml. An alternative with
some web server software is that the files need to be made executable
in order for the SSI to be recognised.  Your system administrator will
be able to help you with these details.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Some server software does not expect a program run by a server side include
to output any headers even though it is being run with 'exec cgi' as
above.  In these cases you are likely to see something like:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
    Content-Type: text/html
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
above your counter.  You can stop the output of this header by changing the
configuration variable $ssi_emit_cgi_headers to 0.  Some servers that
behave like this have already been identified by the NMS developers and
the program will adjust its own behaviour in those cases, however if you
know of one we have  not identified please e-mail the support list below
with the details.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Finally you will need to upload the appropriate image files to a directory on
your web server.  You can use the supplied images or you can make some
yourself with your favourite graphics software.  There are two sets of digits
provided, in GIF and PNG formats, but the images are otherwise the same and 
you only need to upload those files of the format that you choose and
change the configuration variable $digit_ext as appropriate.  The reason
for providing two sets of images is that some people prefer not to use GIF
images due to a patent on the compression method that is used, once the
NMS developers are happy that the PNG images work on the majority of browsers
then the .gif files will probably be removed. 
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
The image files need only to be readable by the webserver so it is quite
safe to change their mode to 0644. 
</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
