<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="ffa" full_name="Free For All Links">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
Free For All Links is a program to maintain a simple database of web links.
Any visitor to the web page can add links to the database.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>ffa.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The main perl script.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file. Instructions on how to install and use ffa.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>database.txt</filename>
       <filedesc>A sample database file.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>links.html</filename>
       <filedesc>A sample HTML file.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFEST</filename>
       <filedesc>List of files.</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
In order for this program to work properly on your webserver it will require
a small amount of configuration before you upload it.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
All of the configuration is done by editing the program file directly, you
can do this in your favourite text editor or notepad if you are on Windows.
You probably don't want to use a wordprocessor to do this unless you are
certain you can save the file as plain text.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Firstly you will need to change the first line of the program:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
   #!/usr/bin/perl -wT
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
so that it points at the proper location of perl on your webserver - your
system administrator or webhosting provider should be able to tell you this.
You only need to change the '/usr/bin/perl' part - all of the rest of the
line must be left exactly as it is.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you can change in ffa.pl which
alter the way that the program works.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$DEBUGGING</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be set to 1 whilst you are installing
                and testing the script. Once the script is live you
                should change it to 0. When set to 1, errors will
                be output to the browser. This is a security risk and
                should not be used when the script is live.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$directory</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The directory path where all of the ffa files are stored.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$linkstitle</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            A title. This will be used on some of the generated pages.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$filename</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The filename of the HTML file that will display the links.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$linksurl</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The public URL to the HTML page that will display the links.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$usedatabase</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            If this is true (i.e. set to 1) we store the links in a 
                database text file as well as in the HTML page. If this is
                false (i.e. set to 0) we store the links only in the HTML
                page.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$database</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The filename of the database where the links are stored.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$sendmail</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            Set to true (i.e. 1) if you want to be notified of new 
                additions to the list of links.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$mailer</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The path to the mailer (probably sendmail) on your system.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$mail_address</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The address to which notifications of new links are sent.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$style</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The URL of a stylesheet to use on generated HTML pages.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$default_section</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The default category that new links will be added to.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>%sections</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            A hash defining the set of sections (or 'categories'). The
                keys are the section identifiers (as found in the comments
                in the HTML file) and the values are the descriptive titles
                of the sections.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$locale</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This determines the language that is used in the date - by
                default this is blank and the language will probably be
                english. The following a list of some possible values,
                however it should be stressed that not all of these will
                be supported on all systems and also this is not a complete
                list:

                      Catalan           ca_ES
                      Croatian          hr_HR
                      Czech             cs_CZ
                      Danish            da_DK
                      Dutc              nl_NL
                      Estonian          et_EE
                      Finnish           fi_FI
                      French            fr_FR
                      Galician          gl_ES
                      German            de_DE
                      Greek             el_GR
                      Hebrew            he_IL
                      Hungarian         hu_HU
                      Icelandic         is_IS
                      Italian           it_IT
                      Japanese          ja_JP
                      Korean            ko_KR
                      Lithuanian        lt_LT
                      Norwegian         no_NO
                      Polish            pl_PL
                      Portuguese        pt_PT
                      Romanian          ro_RO
                      Russian           ru_RU
                      Slovak            sk_SK
                      Slovenian         sl_SI
                      Spanish           es_ES
                      Swedish           sv_SE
                      Thai              th_TH
                      Turkish           tr_TR
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
ffa is installed simply by copying the file ffa.pl into your cgi-bin 
directory. If you don't know where your cgi-bin directory is, then
please ask your system administrator
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You may need to rename ffa.pl to ffa.cgi. Again, your system
administrator will know if this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file. You can
do this by running the command "chmod +x ffa.pl" from your command
line. If you don't have command line access to your web server then there
will probably be an equivalent function in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
The webserver needs write permission for the path you set up in $directory
and also for the $database file. Again, ask your system administrator if
you don't know how to do this.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Then, edit the links.html page and put in on your website. You'll need to
edit the link in the <form> tag so that it points to your copy of ffa.pl.
</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
