<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<nms_program prog_file="rand_text" full_name="Random Text">
  <summary>
    <paragraph>
rand_text chooses a random piece of text from a predefined set and
displays it on a webpage. It is intended to be used as a Server Side
Include program.
</paragraph>
  </summary>
  <files>
         <file>
       <filename>rand_text.pl</filename>
       <filedesc>The main perl script.</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>random.txt</filename>
       <filedesc>A sample text database</filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>README</filename>
       <filedesc>This file. Instructions on how to install and use </filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>rand_text.</filename>
       <filedesc></filedesc>
     </file>
     <file>
       <filename>MANIFEST</filename>
       <filedesc>List of files</filedesc>
     </file>

  </files>
  <configuration>
    <introduction>
    <paragraph>
There are a number of variables that you can change in rand_text.pl which
alter the way that the program works.
</paragraph>
    </introduction>
    <variables>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$DEBUGGING</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            This should be set to 1 whilst you are installing
                and testing the script. Once the script is live you
                should change it to 0. When set to 1, errors will
                be output to the browser. This is a security risk and
                should not be used when the script is live.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$random_file</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The path to the file containing the text to choose from. The
                file random.txt in this distribution is an example.
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>
   <variable>
      <var_name>$delimiter</var_name>
      <description>
         <paragraph>
            The character sequence that separates different pieces of text
                in your text file. The default value ("\n
         </paragraph>
      </description>
   </variable>

    </variables>
  </configuration>
  <installation>
      <paragraph>
rand_text is installed simply by copying the file rand_text.pl 
into your cgi-bin directory. If you don't know where your cgi-bin directory 
is, then please ask your system administrator
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You may need to rename rand_text.pl to rand_text.cgi. Again, your
system administrator will know if this is the case.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
You will probably need to turn on execute permissions to the file. You can
do this by running the command "chmod +x rand_text.pl" from your command
line. If you don't have command line access to your web server then there
will probably be an equivalent function in your file transfer program.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Then, edit your HTML files and wherever you want random text to appear put
the following code:
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
<!--#exec cgi="http://your.host.com/cgi-bin/rand_text.pl"-->
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
This is just an example, so be sure to insert the correct URL of your
rand_text.pl installation.
</paragraph>
<paragraph>
Note: As this is a "Server Side Include" you will need to ensure that your
web server has been configured to support SSI. Also, it's possible that you
may need to rename any files that include SSI calls to give them a different
extension. A common choice is .shtml. Your system administrator will be able
to help you with these details.
</paragraph>
  </installation>
</nms_program>
